<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<law>
    <structure>
        <unit label="title" identifier="18.2" order_by="18.2" level="1">Crimes and Offenses Generally</unit>
        <unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6" level="2">Crimes Involving Fraud</unit>
    </structure>
    <section_number>18.2-186</section_number>
    <catch_line>False statements to obtain property or credit.</catch_line>
    <order_by>00000000009104318.2</order_by>
    <text>
        <section prefix="1">
            Notwithstanding ยง 18.2-186:

			<section prefix="A">A person shall be guilty of a Class 1 misdemeanor if he makes,
			causes to be made or conspires to make directly, indirectly or through an agency, any
			materially false statement in writing, knowing it to be false and intending that it be
			relied upon, concerning the financial condition or means or ability to pay of himself,
			or of any other person for whom he is acting, or any firm or corporation in which he is
			interested or for which he is acting, for the purpose of procuring, for his own benefit
			or for the benefit of such person, firm or corporation, the delivery of personal
			property, the payment of cash, the making of a loan or credit, the extension of a
			credit, the discount of an account receivable, or the making, acceptance, discount, sale
			or endorsement of a bill of exchange or promissory note.</section>

			<section prefix="B">Any person who knows that a false statement has been made in writing
			concerning the financial condition or ability to pay of himself or of any person for
			whom he is acting, or any firm or corporation in which he is interested or for which he
			is acting and who, with intent to defraud, procures, upon the faith thereof.
	
				<section prefix="i" type="table">
				+------------------+--------------------+
				| PERSON           | STATEMENT          |
				+------------------+--------------------+
				| any              | false              |
				| no               | true               |
				+------------------+--------------------+
				</section>
	
			For his own benefit, or for the benefit of the person, firm or corporation in which he
			is interested or for which he is acting, any such delivery, payment, loan, credit,
			extension, discount making, acceptance, sale or endorsement, shall, if the value of the
			thing or the amount of the loan, credit or benefit obtained is $200 or more, be guilty
			of grand larceny or, if the value is less than $200, be guilty of petit
			larceny.</section>
	
			<section prefix="C">Venue for the trial of any person charged with an offense under this
			section may be in the county or city in which (i) any act was performed in furtherance
			of the offense, or (ii) the person charged with the offense resided at the time of the
			offense.</section>
	
			<section prefix="D">As used in this section, "in writing" shall include information
			transmitted by computer, facsimile, e-mail, Internet, or any other electronic medium,
			and shall not include information transmitted by any such medium by voice
			transmission.</section>
		</section>
		<section prefix="2">
			This law shall expire on July 1, 2014.
		</section>
	</text>
	<history>Code 1950, ยง 18.1-125; 1960, c. 358; 1975, cc. 14, 15.</history>
	<metadata>
		<repealed>y</repealed>
		<expiration>2014-07-01</expiration>
	</metadata>
	<tags>
		<tag>lying</tag>
		<tag>fraud</tag>
		<tag>theft</tag>
	</tags>
</law>